#### Ali Harb

Email: <u>ali-harb-gm@hotmail.com</u>
Mobile number: + 971 56 571 2728



#### **Career Objective**

Hospitality professional with over 19 years of hotel experience I have excelled in positions in all aspects of Hotel Operations, Market Strategies, and Revenue Management. In addition to having a well-balanced understanding of the overall business, I am extremely involved and engaged with all aspects of Sales & Marketing including Group, Business Travel, Leisure Business Sales, and Field Marketing. My experience has also allowed me to gain exposure working within a city center, conference center, and resort environment.

#### Skills

- Revenue and Market Share Development
- Strategic Business Planning and Budgeting
- Quality Assurance and Development
- Analysis of financial statement and its impact

#### Education

- Bachelor of Business Administration in Hospitality Management
- Diploma In Hotel Management
- Certified Revenue Manager

## **Core Competence:**

## **Operations Management**

- Identify the areas of improvement in operations and find innovative solutions.
- Formulating monthly/annual goals; short/long term budgets and develop business plans for the achievement of the goals

#### **Guest Relationship Management**

- Building and maintaining cordial business relations with major corporate clients, leisure guest and airline ensuring customer satisfaction by achieving delivery & service norms
- Interacting with the customers to gather their feedback regarding the product's utilities
- · Attending to clients concerns & complaints; undertaking steps to effectively resolve them

## **Team Management**

- Leading, training & monitoring the performance of team members to ensure efficiency in housekeeping operations and meeting individual & group targets.
- To ensure that all Housekeeping staff are fully aware of market needs and trends and that their services & product meet these requirements

#### Administration

- To ensure that all Departmental Operations Manuals are prepared and updated periodically
- To ensure that all rooms related forms and reports are updated in time and forwarded to concern department.

## **Employment history**

# Cluster Rooms Division Manager Sharjah Collection By Mysk (a part of the Kempinski Group)

Nov 2016 up to date

.....

Part of the pre-opening team overlooking rooms, IT, and the revenue department.

Set-up the rooms division department for the three lodges located among the Sharjah emirate, as well as all the IT-related systems and the rate structure for the properties. Playing an essential role in room revenue by setting short middle term targets with the sales team and monitor the room profitability.

# Revenue Manager Mar 2016 to Oct 2016 Sharjah Investment and Development Authority (Shurooq)

Responsible for maximizing the Authority Revenue and open a new revenue stream by developing a revenue plan for each destination along with an online revenue strategy, assist the asset management during the pre-opening/post opining of Shurooq Hotel, review the monthly revenue performance per destination and advice a plan to rectify the shortfalls, create and develop revenue Reporting System for Shurooq.

# Group Director of E-Commerce /E- Revenue Jaz Hotels, Resort, and Cruise

Feb 2014 to Jan 2016

Responsible for maximizing the company's online market penetration by using all the online delivery channels for effective pricing strategies based on future demand forecasts. Build strategic and tactical changes on online Channels that drive business profitability by increasing visitors, improving conversion rates, creating brand awareness and exposure

- Insulation of the booking Engine of 43 hotels
- Successful Direct connectivity with the PMS and 3<sup>rd</sup> party OTA through the Booking Engine
- Creating the Best available rate concept with 365 days demand calendar for all hotels
- Enhance overall pricing strategy to include all market segment and distribution channels
- Effective management of inventory and pricing of all distribution channels including
- Closely monitor competitive pricing and the impact of relative pricing decisions on property performance.
- Analysis of a Weekly, Monthly, Quarterly propriety performance.
- Rate parity and rate compliance regularly monitored for all proprieties.
- Sharing best practices and key learning with Property Sales and Reservations Teams.
- Set a P&P for the online segment
- Increase overall market penetration by 18% VS last year
- Increase online conversion rate by 11% for the major destination
- Improve the online market segment by achieving 12% of total hotel's revenue VS 1% from last year

Responsible for maximizing Company revenue through the development and implementation of effective transient/group inventory and pricing strategies based on future demand forecasts. Build strategic and tactical changes on online Channels that drive business profitability by increasing visitors, improving conversion rates

Director Of Revenue
Millennium & Copthorne - Abu Dhabi

Jan 2011 to Apr 2012

Responsible for Revenue strategy & implementation actions, to be consistent with property and market conditions, Manage the E-commerce team operation, Maintain consistent selling strategy across all channels, evaluating the statistical date and implementing strategy changes

Revenue Manager
Millennium & Copthorne - Doha

Jan 2009 to Jan 2011

Controlling rooms inventory to achieve optimum results in Occupancy, Average Rate, and Room Revenue, Reviewing daily reservations accuracy, rates compliance from segment and source, Determines, develops, monitors, and adjusts sales and pricing strategies, Conducts competitive and demand analyses and provides a critical analysis of chosen strategies, room statistics, and general demand factors to ensure the most effective and efficient balance between demand and availability.

Reservations and Revenue Manager
Four Seasons Hotel & Resort – Damascus

Jan 2007 to Dec 2008

Assume responsibility for the execution of the Reservations Department's policies and procedures and manage the daily operation, Control room, and rate availability per established guidelines to maximize occupancy and revenue. Handle all No-Show billings and disputes.

- Member of the task force team in the region
- Operate and manage the CRS system
- Work with the Sales Department in handling group bookings
- Establish and maintain the conversation tables between PMS and WRO system
- Manage and Drive perfect fill program
- Maintain Rate integrity standards
- Achieve 98 % in Richie mystery shopper program
- Set up PMS Opera V2.0 for propriety
- Upgrade PMS to V2.5

Assistant Reservations Manager
Four Seasons Hotel & Resort – Damascus

Sep 2005 to Dec 2006

Join the hotel during the pre-opening period; help hotel set up the opening price strategy, work out the hotel's budget, and set up hotels on the different booking channels, such as CRS, GDS Assume responsibility for the execution of the Reservations Department's policies and procedures and manage the daily operation.

# PERSONAL INFORMATION

Civil Status: Married Nationality: Syrian

• Children Leen -2004 / Maya 2005

References can be provided on request